<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nagib Tharani</title>
    <link>https://nagibtharani.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nagib Tharani</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 10:04:42 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nagibtharani.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving over to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://nagibtharani.com/blog/moving_over_to_hugo_for_my_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 10:04:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nagibtharani.com/blog/moving_over_to_hugo_for_my_blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had several false starts on blogging over the years. I usually get caught up in blogging for companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I made a commitment to blog for myself and be more active in branding myself online. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen Hugo as the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be the first in 3 part series on why I chose Hugo, and how to setup Hugo and in future, a retrospective on how Hugo is working out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://nagibtharani.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:59:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nagibtharani.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an Electrical Engineer by training. I&amp;rsquo;ve since held a variety of roles from large enterprise and venture backed startups to early stage companies. I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to have worked in and travelled to over 30 countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actively code as a hobby, but my expertise is primarily in TMT and SaaS - Product &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;full stack&amp;rdquo; Business Operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My career started out in the telco space, gaining experience working from both the vendor and operator perspectives - with a lot of field engineering thrown in at the start. From there, I branched out to run my own startups, initially an ASP and then a mobile app company, both in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my return to Canada, I took a position working for Clio, a Bessemer backed SaaS legal tech company as their director of International Expansion - which frequently brought me back to Europe several times, but this time I was domiciled where I was born. Since then I’ve been consulting with companies in a product and business operations capacity from an international perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m heavily biased towards modern SaaS tools and help in both selection, configuration of them. I then establish the workflow processes to get the most benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous roles, and depending on the size of the organization I have been the CEO, COO, to a business operations specialist or general manager.  Those terms best encapsulate the hats I wear in a given role:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product Management (Working with, engaging and adapting products for international markets). With regards to International marketing print initiatives, I love explaining the A-Series of paper formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Expansion - Greenfield operations for companies seeking to expand, taking into account legal, tax, regulatory, business development and marketing aspects. I work with governmental inward investment teams and academic institutions to help companies take advantage of in country resources effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Business Development - Closely tied with the above, but specifically about driving new business and engagement models from strategy and partnership programs, to internationally tailored marketing outreach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Program (Programme in the UK, it&amp;rsquo;s not a spelling error) and Project Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Operations - Typically for smaller companies, helping you start your business properly - from HR and accounting to overall governance.  I pride myself on using best of breed SaaS tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An executive that has solid experience across many disciplines can manage multidisciplinary teams more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My latest hobby project is TailorCV.com - a free service to help you build custom CV’s and track your achievements over time. I built this to scratch my own itch as much as anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>